Malik Tillman

Developer - Designer - Student

(201)705-7860

contact@maliktillman.com
github.com/malik-tillman
maliktillman.com

Prevailing college student currently majoring in Computer Science focusing in design and applying conceptual theories.

Freelance developer and graphic designer, with three years' experience developing for various platforms such Android, Windows, Linux, and Web.

PROJECTS

World Guessing Game: Trivia App

An Android application that uses real-time data to generate unique questions.

Languages: Java, C#, XML, Gradle, HTML, JSON, SQL

- Utilizes a dynamic SQL database and a RESTful API service locally hosted on a self-configured Ubuntu Linux server.
- Database populated by a Java application that parses the internet for real-time data on popular countries and cities throughout the world.
- Composed in Android Studio, the app is responsive to size, version, and utilizes AndroidX.

Preventability in the Cybersecurity Domain

An intensive study on preventable causes of major cyber infrastructure collapses due to security vulnerability.

- Collaborated with industry professionals to research steps companies can take to prevent cyber security attacks.
- Examined previous security breaches within organizations to provide recommendations on strategies companies can implement to eliminate future breaches of the same nature.
- Selected for publication by the National Cybersecurity Student Association.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Mobile Expert

T-Mobile, Jersey City, NJ June 2018 – December 2018 (6 Months)

• Worked as a salesperson for cellular devices and service.

Technical Support Services

Arcadia University IT, Glenside, PA, 2016 –2018 (2 Years)

 Provide technical support, remotely and face-to-face, for faculty, staff, and students of Arcadia University.

SKILLS

Java, C++, C#, SQL, REST API, HTML, CSS JavaScript, Python, and PHP

Android Development

Web Development

Network Administration

Linux

Video Game Development

Information Technology

Video and Photography

Adobe Creative Suite, Blender Cinema 4d

HIGHLIGHTS

Successful member of the Fiver Children's Foundation for over 12 years

Multiple Academic Achievement Scholarships received from top 100 universities

Proficient programmer of top-level languages such as Java, C++, and Java Script

Advanced user of the majority program base provided in **Adobe Creative Commons Suite**

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, *Computer Science* Pace University, Seidenberg School of CS 2018 – 2020 (expected)

Bachelor of Arts, *Computer Science* Arcadia University, Glenside, PA 2016 – 2018

High School Diploma

Bayonne High School, Bayonne, NJ 2012 - 2016

Alumni, *Ten Year Commitment*Fiver Children's Foundation, New York, NY
2006 – 2016